A Guide to the Headquarters Papers of Brigadier-General John Forbes Relating to the Expedition against Fort Duquesne in 1758
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Headquarters Papers of Brigadier-General John Forbes Relating to the Expedition against Fort Duquesne in 1758 1729-1759
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10034
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
In the foreword to his
Writings of General John Forbes(Menasha, Wisconsin: Collegiate Press, 1938)
, Alfred Proctor James discussed the fate of the Forbes office copies relating to the Duquesne expedition. He speculated that the archive may have been turned over to James Glen, Forbes' cousin and executor, a former royal governor of South Carolina, but suggested that there are Forbes papers in the possession of relatives in Scotland.
More than a third of a century later, on October 15, 1974, Sotheby's in London offered for sale at auction, a group of some 530 manuscripts from the headquarters papers of General Forbes, virtually all of which related to the Duquesne expedition. Sotheby was able to say only that the owners descended from James Glen through his niece and heir, Elizabeth Glen, who married George Ramsay, the Eighth Earl of Dalhousie. These papers were purchased for the Tracy W. McGregor Library with funds provided by the Trustees of the McGregor Fund, who have made annual grants for the purchase of additions to the collection since 1939.
It will be immediately apparent that the present archive contains virtually no material after August 1758. This suggests that there is an additional group of papers that has been lost or is in the possession of some other descendant and may be discovered in the future.
Biography
Biographical sketch
John Forbes, the son of Colonel John Forbes of Pittencrief, Dunfermline, Fifeshire, Scotland, and Elizabeth Graham, was probably born in 1707. He was trained in medicine, and on September 25, 1729, received his commission as surgeon in the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons (Scots Greys). In July, 1735, he purchased a cornetcy in a troop of the Regiment. With faithful service in the Scots Greys during the War of Austrian Succession, he was promoted rapidly, reaching the rank of lieutenant-colonel in December, 1750 (he had been given that rank in the Army in December, 1745). In Februaryruary, 1757, Forbes was given the colonelcy of the 17th Foot and shortly thereafter departed for North America, where he served the Earl of Loudoun as adjutant general.
Forbes was made a brigadier by William Pitt in December, 1757, with the responsibility of directing a campaign in 1758 the objective of which was the capture of Fort Duquesne and the clearing of the French from the Ohio River Valley. He proceeded to Philadelphia in April, 1758, to assume direct command of operations and planning for the expedition. After months of building a new road through the wilderness and rugged terrain of western Pennsylvania, of building forts along the way to hold territory and protect his army and its supply posts, Fort Duquesne was finally taken on November 25th, after the French had evacuated and blown it up. General Forbes was a very sick man during the campaign and he died in Philadelphia on March 11, 1759, and was buried there in the chancel of Christ Church.
Item Listing
- Kensington, George R., et al., "George the Second..." Docketed: " John Forbes Surgeon for the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons ", 1729 September 25; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as surgeon to the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons (Scots Greys).
- Hermhausen, George R., et al., "George the Second..." Docketed: "John Forbes Gent Cornet", 1735 July 5; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as cornet in the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons (Scots Greys).
- Court at St. James's, George R., et al., "George the Second..." Docketed: "John Forbess Gent Lieut", 1742 April 23; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as lieutenant in the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons ( Scots Greys).
- Peteghem, George Wade, et al., "George Wade Esqr. Field Marshal...", 1744 September 24; MsS, 1 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as captain in the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons (Scots Greys).
- Court at St. James's, George R, et al., "George the Second..." Docketed: " John Forbes, Esqr:, Deputy Quarter Master General", 1745 December 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as deputy quartermaster general with the rank of lieutenant-colonel in the army.
- Court at St. James's, George R, et al., "George the Second..." Docketed: " John Forbes, Esqr: Major to the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons ", 1746/7 February 3; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as major in the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons (Scots Greys).
- London, H. [William, Eighth Earl of Home?] to "Dear Jock", 1747 January 18; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
- Court at St. James's, George R. "George the Second..." Docketed: " John Forbes, Esqr: Lieutenant Colonel to the Earl of Rothes's Regiment of North British Dragoons ", 1750 November 29; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as lieutenant-colonel of the Royal Regiment of North British Dragoons (Scots Greys).
- Letterbook of Sir John St. Clair, Deputy Quartermaster General of British Forces in North America., 1755 January 12 -1756 December 28; Ms, Bound volume, 316 p. (Box Box 1)
  About one-half of the volume is devoted to correspondence concerning the Expedition against Fort Duquesne under the command of Major General Edward Braddock. Separate inventory available.
- Williamsburg, Edward Braddock to Sir John St. Clair. Docket: "Establishment Carpenters & Rangers 1755", 1755 February 28; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 1)
  Enclosure: "A Copy Establishment for Two Compys. of Carpenters..." 4 p.
- Leith, William Forbes to Hugh Forbes., 1756 August 16; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
  Originally enclosed with 1756 August 18 Loretto, Hu[gh] Forbes to John [Forbes?].
- Loretto, Hu[gh] Forbes to John [Forbes?]., 1756 August 18; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
  Originally enclosed 1756 August 16 William Forbes to Hugh Forbes.
- "Lieutenant Colonel John Forbes. " Docketed: "Lieutenant Colonel John Forbes 's Account to 23d.: February. 1757", 1756 August 20 -1757 February 23; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Loretto, Hu[gh]: Forbes to Forbes., 1756 August 28; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- London, George Ross to Forbes., 1756 December 30; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 1)
- Edinburgh, Fran: Lindsay to Colonel [Forbes], 1757 February 1; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Court at St. James's, George R. "George the Second..." Docketed: " John Forbes Esq. Colonel of the 17th Regt. of Foot ", 1757 February 25; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Forbes' commission as colonel of the Seventeenth Regiment of Foot.
- London, St. James Street, John Dingwall to Forbes., 1757 April 26; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 1)
- Lancaster. "Intelligence given to me by John Hart of Lancaster which has followed the Indian Trade about the Ohio Fort Detroit and the Western Lakes for the space of 30 years thus in presents of Sr. Allen Machline [Sir Allan Maclean ?], the 25th May 1757 at Lancaster ", 1757 May 25; Ms, 4 p. (Box Box 1)
- Boston, St. Clair to Robert Napier, 1757 July 30; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 1)
  Originally laid in the letterbook of Sir John St. Clair.
- Orderly Book "Halifax August 1st-1757...", 1757 August 1-1757 December 16; Ms, 87 p. (Box Box 1)
- Boston [St. Clair?] to [Earl of Loudoun]; Albany [St. Clair?] to Loudoun, 1757 August 7 and 18; L (copies), 2 p. (Box Box 1)
  Originally laid in the letterbook of Sir John St. Clair. The letters are on the same leaf of paper.
- Schenectady, John Godwin. "A Return of the Ammunition sent to Schenectady the 15th November 1757." Docketed: "Return of the Ammunition sent to Schenectady the 15th Novr. 1757", 1757 November 15; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Schenectady, John Godwin. "Return of the Detachment of the Royal Regiment of Artillery ordered to Escort the Ammunition Waggons & to remain at Schenectady; 15th November 1757." Docketed: "Return of the Detachm: of Roy. Artillery: ordered to Escort the ammunitn: Waggons & to remain at Schenectady 15th: November: 1757", 1757 November 15; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Albany, James Abercromby to Forbes, New York. Docket: "Genll. Abercromby Albany November. 27", 1757 November 27; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Fort Edward, William Haviland to Abercromby. Docketed: "Col. Haviland to Genll Abercromby Fort Edward - November. 27", 1757 November 27; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
  Originally enclosed in Abercromby to Forbes, Albany, December. 4, 1757.
- Albany, Abercromby to [Forbes.] Docketed: "Gen. Abercrombie Albany Novr. 28th", 1757 November 28; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 1)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes., New York. Docketed: "Albany Novr. 29th Genll. Abercrombie", 1757 November 29; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 1)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes, New York. 1 p. with ALS., n.d., James Abercrombie, Aide-de-Camp, to Forbes on facing leaf. Docket: "Capt. Abercrombie Albany Novr. 30", 1757 November 30; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 1)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Gen. Abercromby Albany December. 4th", 1757 December 4; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes, New York, 1757 December 14; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Orderly book, "New York Saturday 17th Decemr. 1757....", 1757 December 17-1758 January 18; Ms, 16 p. (Box Box 1)
- New York, Loudoun to Gov. Horatio Sharpe. Docket: "copy Lord Loudoun to Gov. Sharp New York January. 2", 1758 January 2; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 1)
- New York, Loudoun to Edmund Atkin. Docketed: "copy the Earl of Loudoun's letter to Edmond Atkin Esq. New York February. 14th: 1758", 1758 January 14; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 1)
- Albany, Abercromby to [Forbes?] Docketed: "Gen. Abercromby Albany January. 23rd", 1758 January 23; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 1)
- Charlestown, Archibald Montgomery. "Return of the First Highland Battalion Commanded by the Honble Archd Montgomery Lt. Col. Commandant Charles Town South Carolina Januaryry. 24th 1758." Docketed: "Return of the First Highland Battn. commanded by the Honble Archd. Montgomery Lt. Colo. Commandt Charles Town South Carolina Januaryry. 24th 1758", 1758 January 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Charlestown, Thomas Goldsmith. "A Monthly Return of his Majestys Three Independent Companys doing duty in South Carolina and Georgia Charles Town the 24 Januaryuary 1758." Docketed: " A Return of the Three Independt. companys the 24 Januaryry. 1758", 1758 January 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Charlestown, Adam Stephen. "A Monthly Return of ye Virginia Detachment at Charles Town So. Carolina Januaryy. 24th 1758." Docketed: "Monthly Return of the Virginia Detachment Chas. Town So. Carolina the 24th Januaryy 1758", 1758 January 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Charlestown, H. Bouquet. "A Monthly Return of the 2d. Division of the 1st Battalion of the Royal American Regt. commanded by the Earl of Loudoun." Docketed: "Return of the 2d. Division of ye 1st Battalln. of the Royal American Regt: commanded by ye Earl of Loudoun Chas. Town So. Carolina 24 Januaryuary 1758", 1758 January 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genll. Abercromby Albany Januaryy 29th", 1758 January 29; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 1)
- New York. Docketed: "Plan of Instructions for Maj Gen [Peregrine] Hopson. New York. Februaryy. 1758", 1758 February; Ms, 7 p. (Box Box 2)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes, New York. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby Albany February: 7th", 1758 February 7; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Loudoun to John Blair. Docketed: "Extract of a letter from the Earl of Loudoun to the Presidt. of Virginia New York Februaryy 13th: 1758", 1758 February 13; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Loudoun to William Henry Lyttelton. Docketed: "Private extract of a letter from the Earl of Loudoun to Gov. Lyttleton Dated Februaryy. 13th. 1758", 1758 February 13; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Loudoun to Lyttelton. Docketed: "Extract of a letter from the Earl of Lou- doun to Govr. Lyttleton Dated Februaryy. ye 13th. 1758", 1758 February 13; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes, New York. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby Albany Februaryy 14th", 1758 February 14; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Loudoun to Abraham Bosomworth. Docketed: "Earl of Loudoun's letter 15th Februaryy. 1758 copy", 1758 February 15; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Halifax, Alexander Murray to [Forbes] Docketed: " Maj. [Mur]ray - Februaryy 16th", 1758 February 16; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Boston, Nicholas Cox. "A weekly return of recruits raised for the 47th. Regiment commanded by General Lascelles. Boston 19th. Februaryy. 1758", 1758 February 19; MsS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
- Albany, Abercromby to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby Albany February 21st", 1758 February 21; L, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Burlington, William Sparke to Forbes. Docketed: "Majr Sparkes. Februaryy 14", 1758 February 24; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Stratford, Conn. Simon Fraser "Monthly return of the Sixty third Regimt. of Foot, commanded by Lieut. Colo: Commandant Simon Fraser." Docketed: "Monthly return of His Majesties 63d. or Second Highland Battn. Februaryy 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Lancaster, John Stanwix. "Return of five Companies of the first Battalion of His Majesty's Royal American Regiment of Foot whereof His Excellency the Earl of Loudoun is Colonel in Chief. Lancaster the 24th Februaryruary 1758." Docketed: "Colo Stanwix monthly return Februaryy 24th", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Chester Town, Peter Wraxall. "A Monthly return of two of His Majestys Independant Companies of Foot, quartered at Chester Town in Maryland. Februaryruary 24. 1758." Docketed: "Monthly Return of 2 N. York Indt. Comps. quartered at Chester Town Maryland 24 Februaryy. 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Henry Fletcher. "Monthly Return of the Thirty Fifth Regimt. of Foot, Commanded by Lieut. Genl. Chas. Otway." Docketed: "Monthly Return of the 35th Regimt. Philadelpa. 24th Februaryy. 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Augustine Prevost. "A Monthly Return of the 3d. Battn. of the 60th Regimt. of Foot, Commanded by Right Honbl Lord Viscount Howe Februaryry 24th 1758." Docketed: "A Monthly Return of the 3d Battalion of the 60th Regt. 24th Februaryry 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  "Companies-------Quartered
  2 at ------- Jamaica
  1 at ------- Flushing
  1 at ------- New Town
  1 at ------- Bedford & Bushwick
  1 at ------- Bruckland Ferry
  1 at ------- Flatt Bush & New Lotts
  1 at ------- Gravesend & Flatt Lands
  1 at ------- New Utrecht Gravesend Flatt Bush
  Grenadiers detached"
- Frederick Haldimand. "A Monthly Return of the 2nd Battalion of His Majesty's Royal American Regiment, Whereof His Excellency John Earl of Loudoun is Colonel in Chief. From ye 25th Januaryry. to the 24th Februaryruary following 1758, Inclusive." Docketed: "Monthly Return of the 2nd Battn. of the Royal American Regiment -- Annapolis Februaryy. 24th: 1758, 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
  Compys.
  5 at Annapolis
  3 at Redding
  2 at Yorktown
  10 Total"
- Burlington, William Sparke. "Monthly Return of His Majesties 48th Regiment of Foot Commanded by Major General Daniel Webb, Burlington Februaryry. 24th 1758." Docketed: "Monthly Return of His Majesties 48th Regt. of Foot Whereof Major Genl Danl Webb is Colonel, Burlington February. 24th 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Elisabeth Town, W. Hervey. "Monthly Return of His Majesty's 44th Regiment of Foot, Elisabeth-Town 24th: Februaryy: 1758." Docketed: "Monthly Return of His Majesty's 44th Regimt. of Foot Elisabeth Town 24 Februaryy. 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- John Spital. "Monthly Return of the Forces under the Command of Major General Abercromby. 24th Februaryruary 1758." Docketed: "Monthly Return of the fforces under the Command of Major General Abercromby 24th Februaryruary 1758", 1758 February 24; Ms, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- John Rutherford. "Monthly Return of the 4th Batt. Royl. American Regimt. of Foot, Commanded by the Right Honble. the Earl of Loudoun 24 Februaryruary 1758." Docketed: "Monthly Return of the 4th Battalion Royal American Regiment of Foot 24th Februaryruary 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- John Stanwix. "Return of five Companies of the first Battalion of His Majesty's Royal American Regiment of Foot... Lancaster the 24th: Februaryruary 1758", 1758 February 24; MsS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
- Charlestown, William Ogilvie. "A Monthly Return of His Majestys Independent Company Commanded by Capt. William Ogilvie. " Docketed: "Monthly Return of Capt Ogilvie's Compy. 24th Februaryry 1758", 1758 February 25; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
  A second copy is included.
- Albany, Abercromby to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby Albany Februaryy 26th", 1758 February 26; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Halifax, Alexander Murray to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Major Murray Februaryy 28th", 1758 February 28; ALS, 4 p. plus separate address leaf (Box Box 2)
- Halifax, Peregrine Hopson to Forbes. Docketed: "General Hopson Februaryy 28th", 1758 February 28; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Robert Monckton to Alexander Johnstone, 1758 [February 29] Tuesday 4 o'clock; LS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
  Originally enclosed in March 1, 1758, Johnstone to [Forbes].
- William Byrd to Loudoun. Docket: "Copy William Byrd Esqr. Letter to Lord Loudoun March 1758", 1758 March; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Halifax, Alexander Johnstone to [Forbes?]. Docketed: "Mr Johnston Hallifax March 1st", 1758 March 1; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Fort Prince George in the Lower Cherokees, Head Warriors of the Lower Cherokees to the Mohawks. Docket: "Copy Letter from the Cherokees to the Mohawks. Enclosed in Brigr. Genl. Forbes's of the 20t. April 1758", 1758 March 2; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Fort Prince George in the Lower Cherokees, Head Warriors of the Lower Cherokees to Mohawks. Docket: "Letter Lower Cherokees to the Mohawks", 1758 March 2; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Sir Jno. St Clair Philadelphia March 4th", 1758 March 4; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Boston, John Cosnan to Forbes. Docketed: "Capt Cosnan March 9th", 1758 March 9; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Boston, Cosnan to Forbes. Docketed: "Capt Cosnan. Boston March 13th", 1758 March 13; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Albany, Robert Williams to [Forbes?]. Docketed: "Mr. Williams Qr.Mr to be made an ensign in place of Hague", 1758 March 13; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Boston, [J?] Moncrieffe to [Forbes?] Docketed: "Capt Moncrieff Boston March 13", 1758 March 13; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Annapolis, Frederick Haldimand to Forbes. Docketed: "Colo Haldiman March 14th", 1758 March 14; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Richard Peters. "At a Conference held with the Indians in Philadelphia in the Council Chamber on Wednesday the 15th of March 1758." Docketed: "Conference Govr. Denny & Indians", 1758 March 15; MsS (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York. "For the speedy Conveyance of Intelligence throughout the Provinces of New Jersey, Pennsylvania, Maryland, & Virginia...." Docketed: "Couriers posted through the provinces", 1758 March 17; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Forbes to Denny. Docketed: "Copy to Govr. Denny March 20th", 1758 March 20; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Annapolis, Sharpe to Abercromby. Docketed: "Copy Govr. Sharp to Genl Abercromby Annapolis March 20th 1758", 1758 March 20; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Boston, Cosnan to Forbes. Docketed: "C: Cosnan March 21st", 1758 March 21; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, G.C. Wetterstrom to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Capt Wetterstromes time of serving", 1758 March 21; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Charlestown, Lyttelton to Loudoun. Docketed: "Extract of a Letter from Govor. Lytleton to the Earl of Loudoun Chas.town 21: March 1758", 1758 March 21; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Charlestown, William Byrd to Forbes. Docketed: "Colo Byrd So Carolina March 21st R Aprile 22d", 1758 March 21; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Joshua Howell to Christopher Kilby. Docketed: "Mr. Howell to Mr. Kilby Philad: March 21st", 1758 March 21; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, [Forbes] to Denny. Docketed: "Coppy leter to Governr. Denny March 22d", 1758 March 22; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Edmund Atkin to Cunnicahtarkly; Atkin to William Byrd. Docketed: "Copies - Mr. Atkin's Letters to the Cherokee Governor and Mr. Byrd. March 24th. 1758 - enclosed in His Letter to Lord Loudoun of the 25. March 1758", 1758 March 24; L (copy), 6 p. (Box Box 2)
- Charlestown, Edmund Atkin to Byrd with copy of letter from Atkin to Cunnicahtarkty on adjoining leaf. Docketed: "Mr. Atkins letter to Col. Byrd", 1758 March 24; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny to "Col. Washington or the Commanding Officer at Winchester." Docketed: "Gover Denny to Command Officer at Winchester", 1758 March 25; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Charlestown, Edmund Atkin to Loudoun. Docketed: "Copy of a Letter from Edmd. Atkin to the Earl of Loudoun Chas. Town 25 March 1758", 1758 March 25 -April 1; L (copy), 6 p. (Box Box 2)
  Postscript is dated April 1.
- Fort Johnson, Peter Wraxall. "Several Senecas arrived here from their Country in ten days, who having desired a meeting spoke as follows." Docketed: "Intelligence from a Seneca Sachem 25th March 1758", 1758 March 25; Ms (copy), 8 p. (Box Box 2)
- Annapolis, Sharpe to Forbes. Docketed: "Governor Sharp's Annapolis March 27th", 1758 March 27; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Forbes to Abercromby. Docketed: "Copy letter Brigr Forbes to Majr Genll Abercromby. N. York March 29th 1758", 1758 March 29; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Richard Peters, Secretary. "A Verbal Message to the Governor from the Assembly", 1758 March 29; MsS (copy), 1 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny to Forbes. Docketed: "Govr. Dennys letter & verball message Philadelph. March 30th 1758", 1758 March 30; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Fort Loudoun, Thos. Bullitt, John Campbell, et al. "The proceedings of a Council of Officers held at Fort Loudoun in Virginia March 30th 1758." Docketed: "Proceedings of a Council held at Fort Loudoun on Indian Affairs", 1758 March 30; MsS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Brunswick, Robert MacKinen to. Docketed in Forbes's hand: "C: Mackinen Brunswick Aprile 3", 1758 March 30; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 2)
- [Fort Loudoun], Thomas Bullitt to Denny. Docketed: "Capt. Bullitt to Gover Denny", [1758 March 31]; LS (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny. "A Message from the Governor to the Assembly." Docketed: "Copy 3d. April 1758 Governor Denny's Message to the Assembly", 1758 April 3; MsS (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, [Forbes] to Denny. Docketed: "Copy letter to Govr. Denny and to Govr. Sharp Aprile 4th", 1758 April 4; AL (draft), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny to Forbes. Docketed: "Govern Denny's letter Philad: Aprile 4th 1758 Rd the 7th", 1758 April 4; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny to Forbes. Docketed: "Govern Denny's Philad: Aprile 5th 1758 R: Aple 7th", 1758 April 5; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St. Clair Philad: Aprile 5th", 1758 April 5; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- "Extract from a Speech made by Governor Sharpe to the Chief of a Party of Sixty Cherokee Indians." Docketed: "Extract Govr. Sharps Speech to the Cherokees", 1758 April 5; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Annapolis, Sharpe to Forbes. Docketed: "Govr Sharp - Annapolis Aprl 6th 1758 R: 11th", 1758 April 6; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir John St Clair Philad: Aprile 6th", 1758 April 6; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir John St Clair Philad: Aprile 7th", 1758 April 7; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)